[
  {
    "title": "The First Commandment",
    "text": "<strong>Thou shalt have no other gods.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "We should fear, love, and trust in God above all things."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Lord God, author and source of all that is good, give us wisdom to fear Your wrath, strength to love You above all things, and faith to trust in Your promises alone, that by Your grace we may serve You all our days and finally come to inherit Your heavenly kingdom; through Jesus Christ, Your Son, our Lord, who lives and reigns with You and the Holy Ghost, ever one God, now and forever. Amen.",
      "Lord God, You require us to fear, love, and trust in You above all things. Grant unto us undivided hearts to fear Your wrath and so avoid the evil that You abhor. Instead, help us to love what You command and trust in Your promises; through Jesus Christ, Your Son, who lives and reigns with You and the Holy Spirit, one God, world without end. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Second Commandment",
    "text": "<strong>Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord, thy God, in vain.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "We should fear and love God that we may not curse, swear, use witchcraft, lie, or deceive by His name, but call upon it in every trouble, pray, praise, and give thanks."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Holy Father, purify our lips from every misuse of Your name by cursing, swearing, superstition, lying, or deception. Open our mouths to reverence Your holy name, calling upon it in every time of trouble, praying for what You promise to give, praising You for Your glory, and giving thanks to You as the giver of every good and perfect gift; this we ask in the name that gives us access to You, the name of Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "Holy and merciful God, cause us to fear and love You so that we do not curse, swear, use satanic arts, lie, or deceive by Your name, but call upon it in every trouble, pray, praise, and give thanks and so glorify Your name, which alone is holy; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Third Commandment",
    "text": "<strong>Thou shalt sanctify the holy-day.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "We should fear and love God that we may not despise preaching and His Word, but hold it sacred, and gladly hear and learn it."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "We thank You, kind Father, that You give us time to hear Your Holy Word. Grant that fearing and loving You, we may set aside our work to receive Your Son's words, which are spirit and life, and so, refreshed and renewed by the preaching of Your Gospel, we might live in the peace and quietness that come through faith alone; we ask it for the sake of Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "By Your Word and Spirit, draw us away from our restless labor that we might find rest in You alone, merciful God. Grant that, fearing and loving You above all things, we may never despise the preaching of Your Word of Life, but hold it sacred and gladly hear and learn it; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Fourth Commandment",
    "text": "<strong>Thou shalt honor thy father and thy mother.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "We should fear and love God that we may not despise nor anger our parents and masters, but give them honor, serve, obey, and hold them in love and esteem."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Heavenly Father, from whom all fatherhood on earth is given: give unto us gratitude for the gifts of parents and others in authority and the humility to serve, obey, love, and cherish them as they fulfill the duties and responsibilities You have assigned to them in this life; through Your Son, Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "Heavenly Father, from whom all earthly Fatherhood has its source: Look in mercy on Your children that we may never sin against You by despising or angering our parents and others whom You place in authority over us. Give us repentance where we have ignored, neglected, or provoked our parents, and enable us to honor, serve, obey, love, and cherish them as Your instruments for giving us life and blessing; through Jesus Christ, Your Son, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Fifth Commandment",
    "text": "<strong>Thou shalt not kill.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "We should fear and love God that we may not hurt nor harm our neighbor in his body, but help and befriend him in every bodily need [in every need and danger of life and body]."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Lord God, by Your Law You guard and defend every human life from violence and destruction. Give us wisdom never to hurt or harm our neighbors in their bodily life and give us hearts of mercy to help and support them in every physical need; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "God, defender of the weak and helper of the helpless, we implore You to sustain us with Your favor and strengthen us by Your mercy that we might act with tenderness toward our neighbors, never hurting or harming them in their bodies by hateful words, destructive deeds, or neglect of their well-being. Instead, empower us to help and support them in every physical need even as You have shown mercy to us in Your crucified Son in whose name we pray. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Sixth Commandment",
    "text": "<strong>Thou shalt not commit adultery.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "We should fear and love God that we may lead a chaste and decent life in words and deeds, and each love and honor his spouse."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Holy Lord, You instituted marriage in Eden, and by Your Word You uphold and protect this blessed union of man and woman in one flesh. Cause us to honor marriage and put away from us all sinful thoughts, words, and deeds that would dishonor and distort the gift of marriage. Bless all married couples with faithfulness. Hear the prayers of all who seek a godly spouse, and give to us all purity and decency in all things; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "Holy Father, You blessed our first parents in Paradise with the gift of marriage, and by Your Word You continue to unite men and women in this estate which You have hallowed and blessed. Guard us from all dishonorable lust and every sexual sin that we may be pure and decent in all that we say or do. Answer the cries of those who seek a godly spouse, and uphold all married couples in faithfulness that they may honor and love each other and so glorify You; through Jesus Christ, who is the true Bridegroom to His Bride, the Church. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Seventh Commandment",
    "text": "<strong>Thou shalt not steal.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "We should fear and love God that we may not take our neighbor's money or property, nor get them by false ware or dealing, but help him to improve and protect his property and business [that his means are preserved and his condition is improved]."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Lord God, giver of every good and perfect gift, teach us to rejoice in the bounty of Your gifts given to our neighbors and curb our appetite to claim for ourselves by theft or dishonesty the money or possessions You have bestowed on them. Instead, give us cheerful hearts and willing hands to help our neighbors improve and protect their livelihood; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "Father of light and Giver of every good gift, keep us from treating our neighbors' money or possessions as things that we are free to take for ourselves. Instead, give us charity of heart that we might help and assist our neighbors to improve and protect their possessions and income so they may live without want or neediness and so enjoy the blessings that You have bestowed on them; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Eighth Commandment",
    "text": "<strong>Thou shalt not bear false witness against thy neighbor.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "We should fear and love God that we may not deceitfully belie, betray, slander, or defame our neighbor, but defend him, [think and] speak well of him, and put the best construction on everything."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Guard our lips, O Lord, and govern our unruly tongues so that our words about our neighbors are not tainted with falsehood, betrayal, or slander, which would damage their reputation. Instead, give us the wisdom to speak well of our neighbors, defend them, and explain their circumstances and actions in the kindest way; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "God of truth, set a guard over the door of our lips, that our tongues may be purified from sinful speech and sanctified for the words that edify. Give us repentance where we have uttered falsehood, betrayed through exposing secrets, slandered with malicious gossip, or hurt our neighbor's reputation with lies or half-truths. Make us eager and ready to come to the defense of our neighbors, speak well of them, and explain their circumstances and actions in the kindest way. Hear us for the sake of Him who is truth incarnate, Your Son, our Lord, Jesus Christ. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Ninth Commandment",
    "text": "<strong>Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "We should fear and love God that we may not craftily seek to get our neighbor's inheritance or house, and obtain it by a show of [justice and] right, etc., but help and be of service to him in keeping it."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Gracious Giver of every good and perfect gift, restrain our rogue hearts as they too easily are drawn to covetousness, which is idolatry. Break every scheme that would attempt to obtain for ourselves the property that You have given to our neighbors, and grant unto us contentment with the daily bread You have freely and without merit granted to us; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "Heavenly Father, You open Your hand and satisfy the desires of every living creature. Cause us to fear and love You above all things, that our hearts would not covet that which You have given to our neighbors. Rather, lead us to trust in Your provision of daily bread, be content with what You provide, and reject every evil scheme or enticement that would secure for ourselves that which You have given to other. Enable us to serve our neighbors by helping them keep and guard all that You have given to them; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Tenth Commandment",
    "text": "<strong>Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor his man-servant, nor his maid-servant, nor his cattle, nor anything that is his.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "We should fear and love God that we may not estrange, force, or entice away our neighbor's wife, servants, or cattle, but urge them to stay and [diligently] do their duty."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Almighty God, Lord of all that is good and pure: Set our hearts on You alone so that we may not entice or force away the spouse, workers, or animals of our neighbor but urge them to fulfill their duties in the places where You have put them; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Close of the Commandments",
    "text": "",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What Does God Say of All These Commandments?",
        "answer": "He says thus (Exod. 20:5f): I the Lord, thy God, am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity of the fathers upon the children unto the third and fourth generation of them that hate Me, and showing mercy unto thousands of them that love Me and keep My commandments."
      },
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "God threatens to punish all that transgress these commandments. Therefore we should dread His wrath and not act contrary to these commandments. But He promises grace and every blessing to all that keep these commandments. Therefore we should also love and trust in Him, and gladly do [zealously and diligently order our whole life] according to His commandments."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Lord God, in Your holy jealousy You will not share us with any false gods. Unite our hearts to fear Your wrath and never disobey Your Commandments and so incur Your deserved punishment. Enable us to love and trust in You above all things that by Your grace we might receive the blessings You promise to those who keep Your Commandments; through Jesus Christ, your Son, our Lord, who lives and reigns with You and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. Amen.",
      "Holy and merciful God, You have taught us what You would have us do and not do. Pour out Your Holy Spirit on us so that He may bear fruit in our lives and that, remembering Your mercies and Your laws, we may grow in obedience to Your will and in love for You and our neighbor. Help us to follow the example of Your dear Son, Jesus Christ, our Lord, in whose name we pray. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Apostles' Creed - First Article",
    "text": "<strong>I believe in God the Father Almighty, Maker of heaven and earth.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "I believe that God has made me and all creatures; that He has given me my body and soul, eyes, ears, and all my limbs, my reason, and all my senses, and still preserves them; in addition thereto, clothing and shoes, meat and drink, house and homestead, wife and children, fields, cattle, and all my goods; that He provides me richly and daily with all that I need to support this body and life, protects me from all danger, and guards me and preserves me from all evil; and all this out of pure, fatherly, divine goodness and mercy, without any merit or worthiness in me; for all which I owe it to Him to thank, praise, serve, and obey Him. This is most certainly true."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Almighty Maker of heaven and earth: We give You thanks for the gift of our creation in body and soul. You are the giver of eyes, ears, and all our members. You have endowed us with our reason and senses, and in Your mercy You take care of us. For what we need to support this body and life food and drink, house and home, wife and children, land, animals, and all that we have - You richly and daily provide. In Your kind care You defend us against all danger and guard and protect us from all evil. All this You do out of fatherly, divine goodness and mercy, without any merit or worthiness in us. So we implore You, gracious God, to give us faith to acknowledge Your benefits, tongues to thank and praise Your holy name, and lives joyfully given to serve and obey You; through Jesus Christ, Your Son, who lives and reigns with You and the Holy Spirit, one God forever. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Apostles' Creed - Second Article",
    "text": "<strong>And in Jesus Christ, His only Son, our Lord; who was conceived by the Holy Ghost, born of the Virgin Mary; suffered under Pontius Pilate, was crucified, dead, and buried; He descended into hell; the third day He rose again from the dead; He ascended into heaven, and sitteth on the right hand of God the Father Almighty; from thence He shall come to judge the quick and the dead.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "I believe that Jesus Christ, true God, begotten of the Father from eternity, and also true man, born of the Virgin Mary, is my Lord, who has redeemed me, a lost and condemned creature, purchased and won [delivered] me from all sins, from death, and from the power of the devil, not with gold or silver, but with His holy, precious blood and with His innocent suffering and death, in order that I may be [wholly] His own, and live under Him in His kingdom, and serve Him in everlasting righteousness, innocence, and blessedness, even as He is risen from the dead, lives and reigns to all eternity. This is most certainly true."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Lord Jesus Christ, true God, begotten of the Father from all eternity, and true man, born of the Virgin Mary, You have redeemed us lost and condemned persons. For purchasing and winning us from all sin, from death, and from the power of the devil, not with gold or silver but with Your holy, precious blood and with Your innocent suffering and death, we give You thanks. We praise You that You have made us Your own so that we may live under You in Your kingdom and serve You in everlasting righteousness, innocence, and blessedness, just as You are risen from the dead and live and reign to all eternity with Your Father and the Holy Spirit, one God, now forever. Amen.",
      "Lord Jesus Christ, our Brother and Savior, we praise You for rescuing us from sin, death, and the devil's power by Your innocent suffering and death. Thank You for Your great love and undeserved sacrifice that won us, lost and condemned creatures, to be Yours. Give us faith to trust Your reconciling work and live in the knowledge of Your salvation; for You live and reign with the Father and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Apostles' Creed - Third Article",
    "text": "<strong>I believe in the Holy Ghost; one holy Christian Church, the communion of saints; the forgiveness of sins; the resurrection of the body; and the life everlasting. Amen.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "I believe that I cannot by my own reason or strength believe in Jesus Christ, my Lord, or come to Him; but the Holy Ghost has called me by the Gospel, enlightened me with His gifts, sanctified and kept me in the true faith; even as He calls, gathers, enlightens, and sanctifies the whole Christian Church on earth, and keeps it with Jesus Christ in the one true faith; in which Christian Church He forgives daily and richly all sins to me and all believers, and at the last day will raise up me and all the dead, and will give to me and to all believers in Christ everlasting life. This is most certainly true."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Holy Spirit, I give You thanks that You have called me to saving faith in my Lord Jesus Christ through His Gospel, for without You I could never come to Him. By Your words, which are spirit and life; keep me united with my Savior in true faith, always enlightening me with Your gifts; and sanctifying me in body and soul to live for Christ alone; through my Lord Jesus Christ, who lives and reigns with You and the Father, forever one God. Amen.",
      "Lord Jesus, we cannot believe in You by our own reason or strength or come to You, but Your Holy Spirit has called us by the Gospel, enlightened us with His gifts, sanctified and kept us in the true faith. In the same way He calls, gathers, enlightens, and sanctifies the whole Christian Church on earth and keeps it with You in the one true faith. In this Christian Church, the Holy Spirit daily and richly forgives us all our sins. On the Last Day, He will raise all the dead and give all of us who believe in You eternal life. For this we praise You and implore You according to Your promise to send us the Comforter that we might continue firm in this confession. For You live and reign with Him and the Father, one God, now and forever. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Lord's Prayer - Introduction",
    "text": "<strong>Our Father who art in heaven.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "God would thereby [with this little introduction] tenderly urge us to believe that He is our true Father, and that we are His true children, so that we may ask Him confidently with all assurance, as dear children ask their dear father."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Holy Father, with Your words You tenderly invite us to believe that You are our true Father and we are Your true children. Give us boldness and confidence to trust Your promises and so petition You as dear children addressing their dear father; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "Heavenly Father, Your words give us boldness and confidence to acknowledge You as our true Father and ourselves as Your true children. May Your Holy Spirit lead us to trust in Your fatherly goodness, call upon Your name in every need, and glorify You as the author and giver of every good and perfect gift; through Your Son, Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Lord's Prayer - First Petition",
    "text": "<strong>Hallowed be Thy name.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "God's name is indeed holy in itself; but we pray in this petition that it may become holy among us also."
      },
      {
        "question": "How is this done?",
        "answer": "When the Word of God is taught in its truth and purity, and we as the children of God also lead holy lives in accordance with it. To this end help us, dear Father in heaven. But he that teaches and lives otherwise than God's Word teaches profanes the name of God among us. From this preserve us, Heavenly Father."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Heavenly Father, whose name is holy in itself, by your grace grant that it may be kept holy among us also. Cause Your Word to be taught in truth and purity in our midst, and sanctify us by Your truth to live holy lives according to it. Protect us from false teaching and unholy living that would profane Your name among us; through Jesus Christ, Your Son, who lives and reigns with You and the Holy Spirit, ever one God. Amen.",
      "Holy Father, Your name is holy in itself. We pray that through the words we speak about You and through the lives we live as those marked by Your sacred name in Baptism, we may never profane Your name but honor it in all that we say and do; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Lord's Prayer - Second Petition",
    "text": "<strong>Thy kingdom come.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "The kingdom of God comes indeed without our prayer, of itself; but we pray in this petition that it may come unto us also."
      },
      {
        "question": "How is this done?",
        "answer": "When our heavenly Father gives us His Holy Spirit, so that by His grace we believe His holy Word and lead a godly life here in time and yonder in eternity."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Merciful Father, Your kingdom comes by itself without our prayers, but we implore You to let it come to us also. Give us Your Holy Spirit, heavenly Father, that by Your grace we believe Your Word and lead godly lives here in time and hereafter in eternity; through Jesus Christ, Your Son, who lives and reigns with You and the Holy Spirit, ever one God. Amen.",
      "Father in heaven, give us Your Holy Spirit so that we believe Your Holy Word and live as members of Your gracious kingdom here in time and finally, by Your mercy, be brought to live as partakers of Your everlasting reign; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Lord's Prayer - Third Petition",
    "text": "<strong>Thy will be done on earth as it is in heaven.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "The good and gracious will of God is done indeed without our prayer; but we pray in this petition that it may be done among us also."
      },
      {
        "question": "How is this done?",
        "answer": "When God breaks and hinders every evil counsel and will which would not let us hallow the name of God nor let His kingdom come, such as the will of the devil, the world, and our flesh; but strengthens and keeps us steadfast in His Word and in faith unto our end. This is His gracious and good will."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Blessed God, Your good and gracious will is done even without our prayer, but we pray that it may be done among us also. To that end, we petition You, holy Lord, to break and hinder every evil plan and purpose of the devil, the world, and our sinful nature, which do not want us to hallow Your name, or let Your kingdom come. Strengthen and keep us firm in Your Word and faith until we die, and so fulfill in us Your good and gracious will; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "Merciful Father, ruler of all things in heaven and on earth, we acknowledge that Your good and gracious will is done without our prayer. We pray that you would defeat all that opposes Your will: the devil, the world, and our own sinful nature. In Your mercy, we implore you to strengthen and keep us firm in Your word and faith all the days of our lives and bring us at last the inheritance You have prepared for us in Christ Jesus, who lives and reigns with You and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Lord's Prayer - Fourth Petition",
    "text": "<strong>Give us this day our daily bread.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "God gives daily bread, even without our prayer, to all wicked men; but we pray in this petition that He would lead us to know it, and to receive our daily bread with thanksgiving."
      },
      {
        "question": "What is meant by daily bread?",
        "answer": "Everything that belongs to the support and wants of the body, such as meat, drink, clothing, shoes, house, homestead, field, cattle, money, goods, a pious spouse, pious children, pious servants, pious and faithful magistrates, good government, good weather, peace, health, discipline, honor, good friends, faithful neighbors, and the like."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Generous Father, You certainly open Your hand to give daily bread to everyone without our prayers, even to all evil people. We pray that You would lead us to realize this and so receive our daily bread with thanksgiving, recognizing that in Your bountiful goodness You daily and richly supply everything that has to do with the support and needs of our bodies; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "Gracious Father, You open Your hand and satisfy the desire of every living creature. Teach us to acknowledge You as the Lord who provides for all of our needs in body and soul and so give thanks to You for all of Your bountiful gifts; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Lord's Prayer - Fifth Petition",
    "text": "<strong>And forgive us our trespasses as we forgive those who trespass against us.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "We pray in this petition that our Father in heaven would not look upon our sins, nor deny such petitions on account of them; for we are worthy of none of the things for which we pray, neither have we deserved them; but that He would grant them all to us by grace; for we daily sin much, and indeed deserve nothing but punishment. So will we verily, on our part, also heartily forgive and also readily do good to those who sin against us."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Father in heaven, do not look upon our sins or deny our prayers on account of them. We are neither worthy of the things for which we pray, nor have we deserved them, but we ask that You would give them to us by grace, for we daily sin much and deserve nothing but punishment. So we, too, will sincerely forgive and gladly do good to those who sin against us. In Your mercy, hear us, for the sake of Jesus Christ, our Savior. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Lord's Prayer - Sixth Petition",
    "text": "<strong>And lead us not into temptation.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "God, indeed, tempts no one; but we pray in this petition that God would guard and keep us, so that the devil, the world, and our flesh may not deceive us, nor seduce us into misbelief, despair, and other great shame and vice; and though we be assailed by them, that still we may finally overcome and gain the victory."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "God, You tempt no one to sin, so we pray that You would guard and keep us so that the devil, the world, and our sinful nature may not deceive us or mislead us into false belief, despair, and other great shame and vice. Although we are attacked by these things, we pray that, trusting in You alone, we may finally overcome them and win the victory; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "Heavenly Father, guard and keep us from the assaults of the devil, the deception of the world, and the desires of our sinful nature. Protect us that we may not be deceived or misled by lies about You, be overcome by despair of Your mercy, or be seduced into a way of life that leads only to death. Shield us by Your grace and strengthen us by Your Word and Spirit that we may withstand every attack and finally win the victory; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Lord's Prayer - Seventh Petition",
    "text": "<strong>But deliver us from evil.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "We pray in this petition, as in a summary, that our Father in heaven would deliver us from all manner of evil, of body and soul, property and honor, and at last, when our last hour shall come, grant us a blessed end, and graciously take us from this vale of tears to Himself into heaven."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Our Father in heaven, rescue us from every evil of body and soul, possessions and reputation, and finally, when our last hour comes, give us a blessed end and graciously take us from this valley of sorrow to Yourself in heaven; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "Father in heaven, look on our neediness with the eyes of Your mercy and compassion. Rescue us from everything that would cause harm and destruction to us both physically and spiritually. Keep us in the true faith and finally bring us through the disappointments and sorrows fo this life to live with You forever; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Lord's Prayer - Conclusion",
    "text": "<strong>For Thine is the kingdom and the power and the glory forever and ever. Amen.</strong>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does this mean?",
        "answer": "That I should be certain that these petitions are acceptable to our Father in heaven and heard; for He Himself has commanded us so to pray, and has promised that He will hear us. Amen, Amen; that is, Yea, yea, it shall be so."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Father in heaven, give us the certainty that the petitions we make according to Your command and promise are pleasing to You and are heard by You, s that with all boldness and confidence we might say: Amen, amen. Yes, yes, it shall be so; through Your Son, Jesus Christ, who has taught us to pray in this way. Amen.",
      "Our Father in heaven, grant us certainty to pray according to Your command and in the confidence that You have promised to hear us; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "Holy Baptism - Part 1",
    "text": "",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What is Baptism?",
        "answer": "Baptism is not simple water only, but it is the water comprehended in God's command and connected with God's Word."
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is that word of God?",
        "answer": "Christ, our Lord, says in the last chapter of Matthew : Go ye into all the world and teach all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Lord Jesus Christ, You instituted Baptism, which is not just plain water but water included in Your command and combined with Your word when You said, 'Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.' Grant us always to cherish our Baptism, trusting in the promises You make to us there, and so by this gift come to receive the inheritance of eternal life; for You live and reign with the Father and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. Amen.",
      "Gracious Father, thank You for the gift of Baptism, which Your Son has established by His Word and promise. Teach us to treasure all that Jesus has done for us in His cross and resurrection. Give us confidence that through our Baptism we bear Your holy name and so are Your holy children for time and eternity; through the same Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "Holy Baptism - Part 2",
    "text": "",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does Baptism give or profit?",
        "answer": "It works forgiveness of sins, delivers from death and the devil, and gives eternal salvation to all who believe this, as the words and promises of God declare."
      },
      {
        "question": "Which are such words and promises of God?",
        "answer": "Christ, our Lord, says in the last chapter of Mark : He that believeth and is baptized shall be saved; but he that believeth not shall be damned."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Lord Jesus Christ, by Your death You have purchased and won for us forgiveness of sins, rescuing us from death and the devil and obtaining eternal salvation which You now work in Baptism. Give us Your Spirit that we may believe what You have said, 'Whoever believes and is baptized will be saved,' and so receive these gifts of forgiveness of sins, victory over death and the devil, and eternal salvation, as Your words and promises declare.",
      "Lord Jesus Christ, You have forgiven our sins by Your blood, rescued us from Satan, and won for us eternal life and salvation in Your resurrection. As You bestow these gifts on us in Baptism, grant that in life and death we may always cling to our Baptism, trusting in Your promises, and finally be brought into Your heavenly kingdom."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "Holy Baptism - Part 3",
    "text": "",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "How can water do such great things?",
        "answer": "It is not the water indeed that does them, but the word of God which is in and with the water, and faith, which trusts such word of God in the water. For without the word of God the water is simple water and no baptism. But with the word of God it is a baptism, that is, a gracious water of life and a washing of regeneration in the Holy Ghost, as St. Paul says, Titus, chapter three: By the washing of regeneration and renewing of the Holy Ghost, which He shed on us abundantly through Jesus Christ, our Savior, that, being justified by His grace, we should be made heirs according to the hope of eternal life. This is a faithful saying."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Lord Christ, it is certainly not just water, but the Word of God in the water that does these great things, along with the faith which trusts this Word of God in the water, for without God's Word the water is plain water and no Baptism. We confess and trust that with Your Word, this water is a Baptism, that is, a life-giving water, rich in grace, and a washing of new birth in the Holy Spirit... Give us hearts of faith to cling to this trustworthy saying, not doubting but firmly believing that this Baptism now saves us. Hear us, for we pray in Your name, Lord Jesus.",
      "O God our Father, You have saved us through the washing of rebirth and renewal, which You have poured out on us in our Baptism into Your Son. We thank you for this life-giving water, rich in grace by Your trustworthy promise. Give us faith always to trust Your Word in the water that, justified by grace, we remain heirs of eternal life; through the same Jesus Christ, Your Son, our Lord."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "Holy Baptism - Part 4",
    "text": "",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What does such baptizing with water signify?",
        "answer": "It signifies that the old Adam in us should, by daily contrition and repentance, be drowned and die with all sins and evil lusts, and, again, a new man daily come forth and arise; who shall live before God in righteousness and purity forever."
      },
      {
        "question": "Where is this written?",
        "answer": "St. Paul says Romans, chapter 6 : We are buried with Christ by Baptism into death, that, like as He was raised up from the dead by the glory of the Father, even so we also should walk in newness of life."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Lord God, You have taught us through Your holy apostle. Cause the old Adam in us to be drowned by daily contrition and repentance with all sins and evil desires, so that a new man might daily emerge and arise to live before You in righteousness and purity forever; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
      "Heavenly Father, You have forgiven our sins, rescued us from death and the devil, and given us eternal life by Baptism into the death and resurrection of Your beloved Son. Strengthen our faith, so that we daily put to death all sins and evil desires and, trusting Your sure promises, are raised to live before You in righteousness and purity. Finally, bring us to the fulfillment of our Baptism in the resurrection of the body to life everlasting; through Your Son, Jesus Christ, our Lord."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "Confession",
    "text": "",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What is Confession?",
        "answer": "Confession embraces two parts: the one is, that we confess our sins; the other, that we receive absolution, or forgiveness, from the confessor, as from God Himself, and in no wise doubt, but firmly believe, that our sins are thereby forgiven before God in heaven."
      },
      {
        "question": "What sins should we confess?",
        "answer": "Before God we should plead guilty of all sins, even of those which we do not know, as we do in the Lord's Prayer. But before the confessor we should confess those sins alone which we know and feel in our hearts."
      },
      {
        "question": "Which are these?",
        "answer": "Here consider your station according to the Ten Commandments, whether you are a father, mother, son, daughter, master, mistress, a man-servant or maid-servant; whether you have been disobedient, unfaithful, slothful; whether you have grieved any one by words or deeds; whether you have stolen, neglected, or wasted aught, or done other injury."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Holy and merciful Father, You teach us that if we do not confess our sins, the truth is not in us. Grant us honest hearts to plead guilty of all sins, even those of which we are unaware as we do in the Lord's Prayer-but also give us courage to confess before the pastor those sins which we know and feel in our hearts. Having confessed our sins, give us ears to hear and hearts to receive Your absolution; through Jesus Christ, Your Son, our Lord. Amen.",
      "Lord Jesus Christ, I give You thanks that my sins are forgiven before Your Father in heaven. By the Holy Spirit, give me grace to trust in Your promises and so live in the freedom and peace that You have won for me in Your death and resurrection."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "The Office of the Keys",
    "text": "",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What is the Office of the Keys?",
        "answer": "The Office of the Keys is that special authority which Christ has given to His Church on earth to forgive the sins of repentant sinners, but to withhold forgiveness from the unrepentant as long as they do not repent."
      },
      {
        "question": "What do you believe according to these words?",
        "answer": "I believe that when the called ministers of Christ deal with us by His divine command... this is just as valid and certain, even in heaven, as if Christ our dear Lord dealt with us Himself."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Heavenly Father, You delivered Your Son for our offenses and raised Him for our justification. Grant that we may also trust in the word of forgiveness which You have given to Your pastors to proclaim, that clinging to Your good and gracious promises, we might be brought to eternal life; through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "Sacrament of the Altar - What is it?",
    "text": "",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What is the Sacrament of the Altar?",
        "answer": "It is the true body and blood of our Lord Jesus Christ, under the bread and wine, for us Christians to eat and to drink, instituted by Christ Himself."
      },
      {
        "question": "Where is this written?",
        "answer": "The holy Evangelists, Matthew, Mark, Luke, and St. Paul, write thus: Our Lord Jesus Christ, the same night in which He was betrayed, took bread: and when He had given thanks, He brake it, and gave it to His disciples, and said, Take, eat; this is My body, which is given for you. This do in remembrance of Me_. _After the same manner also He took the cup, when He had supped, gave thanks, and gave it to them, saying, Take, drink ye all of it. This cup is the new testament in My blood, which is shed for you for the remission of sins. This do ye, as oft as ye drink it, in remembrance of Me."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Lord Jesus Christ, on the night of Your betrayal, You established the Supper of Your Body and Blood for us Christians to eat and to drink. Give us faith to trust in the words of Your testament and so rightly receive the fruits of Your suffering and death and through Your merit finally be brought to rejoice in the marriage feast of the Lamb, where You live and reign with the Father and the Spirit forever.",
      "Lord Jesus Christ, on the solemn night of Your betrayal, You established the Sacrament, giving us Your true Body and Blood under bread and wine for us Christians to eat and drink. We praise You for this wondrous testament and pray that You would lead us to eat and drink Your Body and Blood, trusting in Your promise alone; for You live and reign with the Father and the Holy Spirit, ever one God."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "Sacrament of the Altar - The Benefit",
    "text": "",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "What is the benefit of such eating and drinking?",
        "answer": "That is shown us in these words: Given, and shed for you, for the remission of sins; namely, that in the Sacrament forgiveness of sins, life, and salvation are given us through these words. For where there is forgiveness of sins, there is also life and salvation."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Your holy words, Lord Jesus, 'given and shed for you for the forgiveness of sins' bestow on all who believe forgiveness of sins in which there is life with You and salvation in the resurrection of our bodies. Cause us to cling to Your words and so know that, on account of Your Passion, our sins are forgiven, our lives are redeemed from death, and our destiny in Your heavenly kingdom is made certain; for You live and reign with the Father and the Holy Spirit, ever one God.",
      "Lord Jesus Christ, You suffered in Your holy Body and shed Your precious Blood to redeem Your fallen creatures. Grant us to come often to Your Supper, trusting in Your promise, and so to receive to our everlasting benefit the gifts You give in Your Body and Blood: the forgiveness of our sins, life with You, and eternal salvation; for You live and reign with the Father and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "Sacrament of the Altar - The Power",
    "text": "",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "How can bodily eating and drinking do such great things?",
        "answer": "It is not the eating and drinking, indeed, that does them, but the words which stand here, namely: Given, and shed for you, for the remission of sins. Which words are, beside the bodily eating and drinking, as the chief thing in the Sacrament; and he that believes these words has what they say and express, namely, the forgiveness of sins."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Lord Jesus Christ, as we eat Your holy Body and drink Your holy Blood, draw our hearts to trust in Your promise that Your Body and Blood were given and shed for the forgiveness of our sins. Give us the confidence that whoever believes Your words has exactly what they say, 'forgiveness of sins'; for You live and reign with the Father and the Holy Spirit, ever one God.",
      "Lord Jesus Christ, You give Your Body and Blood under bread and wine that we may know with certainty that our sins are forgiven by Your atoning sacrifice on the cross. Grant us so to eat Your Body and drink Your Blood, trusting in Your words that we may receive what You declare the forgiveness of sins and so live in You even as You live and reign with the Father and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "Sacrament of the Altar - Worthiness",
    "text": "",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "Who, then, receives such Sacrament worthily?",
        "answer": "Fasting and bodily preparation is, indeed, a fine outward training; but he is truly worthy and well prepared who has faith in these words: Given, and shed for you, for the remission of sins. But he that does not believe these words, or doubts, is unworthy and unfit; for the words For you require altogether believing hearts."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": [
      "Lord Christ, grant that we may never come to Your altar trusting in our own righteousness or reliant on our own worthiness. Fasting and bodily preparation are fine outward training to discipline the flesh, but they can never make us worthy in Your eyes. Free us from false belief and misplaced trust, and in Your mercy bring us to repentance, deliver us from doubt, and comfort our consciences with Your forgiveness; for You live and reign with the Father and the Holy Spirit, ever one God.",
      "Lord Jesus Christ, I have no worthiness of my own to merit the eating and drinking of Your holy Body and precious Blood. Trusting not in my righteousness but only in Your promise of the forgiveness of sins, I come to Your altar imploring You for mercy that, delivered from Your wrath and condemnation, I might live for You alone, always giving thanks for Your undeserved benefits, and finally be brought to praise You forever at the heavenly banquet."
    ]
  },
  {
    "title": "Morning Prayer",
    "text": "<strong>How the head of the family should teach his household to pray morning and evening.</strong><br><br>In the morning, when you rise, you shall bless yourself with the holy cross and say:<br><br>In the name of God the Father, Son, and Holy Ghost. Amen.<br><br>Then, kneeling or standing, repeat the Creed and the Lord's Prayer. If you choose, you may, in addition, say this little prayer:<br><br>I thank Thee, my Heavenly Father, through Jesus Christ, Thy dear Son, that Thou hast kept me this night from all harm and danger; and I pray Thee to keep me this day also from sin and all evil, that all my doings and life may please Thee. For into Thy hands I commend myself, my body and soul, and all things. Let Thy holy angel be with me, that the Wicked Foe may have no power over me. Amen.<br><br>Then go to your work with joy, singing a hymn, as the Ten Commandments, or what your devotion may suggest.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Evening Prayer",
    "text": "<strong>How the head of the family should teach his household to pray morning and evening.</strong><br><br>In the evening, when you go to bed, you shall bless yourself with the holy cross and say:<br><br>In the name of God the Father, Son, and Holy Ghost. Amen.<br><br>Then, kneeling or standing, repeat the Creed and the Lord's Prayer. If you choose, you may, in addition, say this little prayer:<br><br>I thank Thee, my Heavenly Father, through Jesus Christ, Thy dear Son, that Thou hast graciously kept me this day, and I pray Thee to forgive me all my sins, where I have done wrong, and graciously keep me this night. For into Thy hands I commend myself, my body and soul, and all things. Let Thy holy angel be with me, that the Wicked Foe may have no power over me. Amen.<br><br>Then go to sleep promptly and cheerfully.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Asking a Blessing",
    "text": "<strong>How the Head of the Family Should Teach His Household to Ask a Blessing and Return Thanks.</strong><br><br>The children and servants shall go to the table with folded hands and reverently, and say:<br><br>The eyes of all wait upon Thee, O Lord; and Thou givest them their meat in due season; Thou openest Thine hand, and satisfiest the desire of every living thing.<br><br>Note: To satisfy the desire means that all animals receive so much to eat that they are on this account joyful and of good cheer; for care and avarice hinder such satisfaction.<br><br>Then the Lord's Prayer, and the prayer here following:<br><br>Lord God, Heavenly Father, bless us and these Thy gifts, which we take from Thy bountiful goodness, through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Returning Thanks",
    "text": "<strong>How the Head of the Family Should Teach His Household to Ask a Blessing and Return Thanks.</strong><br><br>Likewise also after the meal they shall reverently and with folded hands say:<br><br>O give thanks unto the Lord, for He is good; for His mercy endureth forever. He giveth food to all flesh; He giveth to the beast his food, and to the young ravens which cry. He delighteth not in the strength of the horse; He taketh not pleasure in the legs of a man. The Lord taketh pleasure in them that fear Him, in those that hope in His mercy.<br><br>Then the Lord's Prayer and the prayer here following:<br><br>We thank Thee, Lord God, Father, through Jesus Christ, our Lord, for all Thy benefits, who livest and reignest forever and ever. Amen.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: For Bishops, Pastors, and Preachers",
    "text": "A bishop must be blameless, the husband of one wife, vigilant, sober, of good behavior, given to hospitality, apt to teach; not given to wine, no striker, not greedy of filthy lucre; but patient, not a brawler, not covetous; one that ruleth well his own house, having his children in subjection with all gravity; not a novice; holding fast the faithful Word as he hath been taught, that he may be able by sound doctrine both to exhort and to convince the gainsayers. <bible-ref>1 Tim. 3:2ff</bible-ref> ; <bible-ref>Titus 1:6</bible-ref>.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: What the Hearers Owe to Their Pastors",
    "text": "Even so hath the Lord ordained that they which preach the Gospel should live of the Gospel. <bible-ref>1 Cor. 9:14</bible-ref>. Let him that is taught in the Word communicate unto him that teacheth in all good things. <bible-ref>Gal. 6:6</bible-ref>. Let the elders that rule well be counted worthy of double honor, especially they who labor in the Word and doctrine. For the Scripture saith, Thou shalt not muzzle the ox that treadeth out the corn; and the laborer is worthy of his reward. <bible-ref>1 Tim. 5:17-18</bible-ref>. Obey them that have the rule over you, and submit yourselves; for they watch for your souls as they that must give account, that they may do it with joy and not with grief; for that is unprofitable for you. <bible-ref>Heb. 13:17</bible-ref>.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: Concerning Civil Government",
    "text": "Let every soul be subject unto the higher powers. For the power which exists anywhere is ordained of God. Whosoever resisteth the power resisteth the ordinance of God; and they that resist shall receive to themselves damnation. For he beareth not the sword in vain; for he is the minister of God, a revenger to execute wrath upon him that doeth evil. Rom. 13:1-4.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: What Subjects Owe to the Magistrates",
    "text": "Render unto Caesar the things which are Caesar's. Matt. 22:21. Let every soul be subject unto the higher powers, etc. Wherefore ye must needs be subject, not only for wrath, but also for conscience' sake. For, for this cause pay ye tribute also; for they are God's ministers, attending continually upon this very thing. Render therefore to all their dues: tribute to whom tribute is due; custom, to whom custom; fear, to whom fear; honor, to whom honor. Rom. 13:1,5ff. I exhort, therefore, that, first of all, supplications, prayers, intercessions, and giving of thanks be made for all men; for kings and for all that are in authority, that we may lead a quiet and peaceable life in all godliness and honesty. 1 Tim. 2:1f Put them in mind to be subject to principalities and powers, etc. Titus 3:1. Submit yourselves to every ordinance of man for the Lord's sake, whether it be to the king as supreme, or unto governors as unto them that are sent by him, etc. 1 Pet. 2:13f",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: For Husbands",
    "text": "Ye husbands, dwell with your wives according to knowledge, giving honor unto the wife, as unto the weaker vessel, and as being heirs together of the grace of life, that your prayers be not hindered. <bible-ref>1 Pet. 3:7</bible-ref>. And be not bitter against them. <bible-ref>Col. 3:9</bible-ref>.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: For Wives",
    "text": "Wives, submit yourselves unto your own husbands, as unto the Lord, even as Sarah obeyed Abraham, calling him lord; whose daughters ye are, as long as ye do well, and are not afraid with any amazement. <bible-ref>1 Pet. 3:6</bible-ref>; <bible-ref>Eph. 5:22</bible-ref>.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: For Parents",
    "text": "Ye fathers, provoke not your children to wrath, but bring them up in the nurture and admonition of the Lord. <bible-ref>Eph. 6:4</bible-ref>.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: For Children",
    "text": "Children, obey your parents in the Lord; for this is right. Honor thy father and mother; which is the first commandment with promise: that it may be well with thee, and thou mayest live long on the earth. <bible-ref>Eph. 6:1-3</bible-ref>.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: For Male and Female Servants, Hired Men, and Laborers",
    "text": "Servants, be obedient to them that are your masters according to the flesh, with fear and trembling, in singleness of your heart, as unto Christ; not with eye-service, as men-pleasers, but as the servants of Christ, doing the will of God from the heart; with good will doing service as to the Lord, and not to men; knowing that whatsoever good thing any man doeth, the same shall he receive of the Lord, whether he be bond or free. <bible-ref>Eph. 6:5ff</bible-ref> ; <bible-ref>Col. 3:22</bible-ref>.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: For Masters and Mistresses",
    "text": "Ye masters, do the same things unto them, forbearing threatening, knowing that your Master also is in heaven; neither is there respect of persons with Him. <bible-ref>Eph. 6:9</bible-ref>; <bible-ref>Col. 4:1</bible-ref>.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: For Young Persons in General",
    "text": "Likewise, ye younger, submit yourselves unto the elder. Yea, all of you be subject one to another, and be clothed with humility; for God resisteth the proud, and giveth grace to the humble. Humble yourselves, therefore, under the mighty hand of God that He may exalt you in due time. <bible-ref>1 Pet. 5:5-6</bible-ref>.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: For Widows",
    "text": "She that is a widow indeed, and desolate, trusteth in God, and continueth in supplications and prayers night and day. But she that liveth in pleasure is dead while she liveth. <bible-ref>1 Tim. 5:5-6</bible-ref>.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Table of Duties: For All in Common",
    "text": "Thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself. Herein are comprehended all the commandments. <bible-ref>Rom. 13:8ff</bible-ref> And persevere in prayer for all men. <bible-ref>1 Tim. 2:1-2</bible-ref>.",
    "questions_and_answers": [],
    "prayers": []
  },
  {
    "title": "Christian Questions with Their Answers",
    "text": "<strong>Prepared by Dr. Martin Luther for those who intend to go to the Sacrament</strong><br><br>[The Christian Questions with Their Answers, designating Luther as the author, first appeared in an edition of the Small Catechism in 1551, five years after Luthers death].<br><br><em>After confession and instruction in the Ten Commandments, the Creed, the Lord's Prayer, and the Sacraments of Baptism and the Lord's Supper, the pastor may ask, or Christians may ask themselves these questions:</em>",
    "questions_and_answers": [
      {
        "question": "1. Do you believe that you are a sinner?",
        "answer": "Yes, I believe it. I am a sinner."
      },
      {
        "question": "2. How do you know this?",
        "answer": "From the Ten Commandments, which I have not kept."
      },
      {
        "question": "3. Are you sorry for your sins?",
        "answer": "Yes, I am sorry that I have sinned against God."
      },
      {
        "question": "4. What have you deserved from God because of your sins?",
        "answer": "His wrath and displeasure, temporal death, and eternal damnation. See <bible-ref>Romans 6:21</bible-ref>,<bible-ref>23</bible-ref>."
      },
      {
        "question": "5. Do you hope to be saved?",
        "answer": "Yes, that is my hope."
      },
      {
        "question": "6. In whom then do you trust?",
        "answer": "In my dear Lord Jesus Christ."
      },
      {
        "question": "7. Who is Christ?",
        "answer": "The Son of God, true God and man."
      },
      {
        "question": "8. How many Gods are there?",
        "answer": "Only one, but there are three persons: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit."
      },
      {
        "question": "9. What has Christ done for you that you trust in Him?",
        "answer": "He died for me and shed His blood for me on the cross for the forgiveness of sins."
      },
      {
        "question": "10. Did the Father also die for you?",
        "answer": "He did not. The Father is God only, as is the Holy Spirit; but the Son is both true God and true man. He died for me and shed his blood for me."
      },
      {
        "question": "11. How do you know this?",
        "answer": "From the holy Gospel, from the words instituting the Sacrament, and by His body and blood given me as a pledge in the Sacrament."
      },
      {
        "question": "12. What are the Words of Institution?",
        "answer": "Our Lord Jesus Christ, on the night when He was betrayed, took bread and when He had given thanks, He broke it and gave it to the disciples and said: Take eat; this is My body, which is given for you. This do in remembrance of Me. In the same way also He took the cup after supper, and when He had given thanks, He gave it to them, saying: Drink of it, all of you; this cup is the new testament in My blood, which is shed for you for the forgiveness of sins. This do, as often as you drink it, in remembrance of Me.\""
      },
      {
        "question": "13. Do you believe, then, that the true body and blood of Christ are in the Sacrament?",
        "answer": "Yes, I believe it."
      },
      {
        "question": "14. What convinces you to believe this?",
        "answer": "The word of Christ: Take, eat, this is My body; drink of it, all of you, this is My blood."
      },
      {
        "question": "15. What should we do when we eat His body and drink His blood, and in this way receive His pledge?",
        "answer": "We should remember and proclaim His death and the shedding of His blood, as He taught us: This do, as often as you drink it, in remembrance of Me."
      },
      {
        "question": "16. Why should we remember and proclaim His death?",
        "answer": "First, so that we may learn to believe that no creature could make satisfaction for our sins. Only Christ, true God and man, could do that. Second, so we may learn to be horrified by our sins, and to regard them as very serious. Third, so we may find joy and comfort in Christ alone, and through faith in Him be saved."
      },
      {
        "question": "17. What motivated Christ to die and make full payment for your sins?",
        "answer": "His great love for His Father and for me and other sinners, as it is written in John 14; Romans 5; Galatians 2 and Ephesians 5."
      },
      {
        "question": "18. Finally, why do you wish to go to the Sacrament?",
        "answer": "That I may learn to believe that Christ, out of great love, died for my sin, and also learn from Him to love God and my neighbor."
      },
      {
        "question": "19. What should admonish and encourage a Christian to receive the Sacrament frequently?",
        "answer": "First, both the command and the promise of Christ the Lord. Second, his own pressing need, because of which the command, encouragement, and promise are given."
      },
      {
        "question": "20. But what should you do if you are not aware of this need and have no hunger and thirst for the Sacrament?",
        "answer": "To such a person no better advice can be given than this: first, he should touch his body to see if he still has flesh and blood. Then he should believe what the Scriptures say of it in Galatians 5 and Romans 7. Second, he should look around to see whether he is still in the world, and remember that there will be no lack of sin and trouble, as the Scriptures say in John 15-16 and in 1 John 2 and 5. Third, he will certainly have the devil also around him, who with his lying and murdering day and night will let him have no peace, within or without, as the Scriptures picture him in John 8 and 16; 1 Peter 5; Ephesians 6; and 2 Timothy 2."
      }
    ],
    "prayers": []
  }
]
